Robert Smith

Correctional Counselor

Phone (123) 456 78 99
Email: info@qwikresume.com
Website: www.qwikresume.com
LinkedIn: linkedin.com/qwikresume
Address: 1737 Marshville Road, Alabama

SUMMARY

Resourceful and dedicated with motivational leadership, training and employee supervision experience. 19+ years in corrections and law enforcement. Hardworking who employs sound judgment and verbal de- escalation tactics to keep order and avoid dangerous situations. Dedicated to continuous process improvement in the face of rapidly evolving and changing markets.

SKILLS

Medication Distribution, MS Office.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Correctional Counselor

ABC Corporation - January 2000 - August 2013

- · Maintained the custody and control of 296 inmates housed in the housing in unit.
- Maintained a caseload of 180 inmates as Correctional Counselor in charge of Classification ensuring they were properly housed and assigning them to appropriate programs.
- Prepared Board Reports for inmates sentenced to Life in Prison scheduled for Parole hearings.
- Determined disciplinary sentences.
- Conducted routine and emergency head counts.
- Inspected work sites and crew trucks for contraband, cleanliness and safety.
- Completed intake paperwork, fingerprints and searches.

Correctional Counselor

Delta Corporation - 1995 - 2000

- To provide security for the staff as well as the residents To assist the officers with any problems that may occur within the unit To provide assist.
- Worked one-on-one with clients to develop success plans.
- Worked to assist in changing their lives and instilling protective factors to minimize risk.
- Was the only employee to receive an outstanding rating on my performance evaluation during my tenure.
- Advisory Board Positions Board of Directors Dental Select Sealants for Smiles 2009-Present.
- Process inmate visitation requests, verify inmate accounts, assist case manager, maintain safety and security of facility, maintain logbooks.
- Serves in a mental health capacity by helping individuals deal with problems and addictions like substance abuse.

EDUCATION

Associate of Arts in Liberal Arts - (West Hills College - Coalinga, CA)